Shantanu Mazumder, EIT

Toronto, Ontario (647) 657 1427 shantanu1.mazumder@protonmail.com

Professional Summary

Mechanical Assembly Technician with 6 years of experience in manufacturing setting, including 3 years in process development and product development roles. Lean Six Sigma Greenbelt certified, certified optical surface quality Subject Matter Expert (SME), serve as a 5S + 1 auditor for other departments, and recognized for writing an Excel VBA macro that reduced project time from 1 year to 1 week. Excellent communications and interpersonal abilities, demonstrated team-player on crossfunctional teams, and self-motivated creative and innovative problem-solver.

Work Experience

Mechanical Assembly Technician

May 2022 to Present

L3Harris Wescam Inc.

- Build state of the art IR surveillance camera for use in military and law enforcement systems.
- Perform technical investigations to isolate and correct issues during building and testing phases.

Optical CNC Technologist

February 2018 to May 2022

L3Harris Wescam Inc.

- Improved process efficiency by writing an Excel macro to sort data for 1,000+ test plates that reduced project time from an estimated 1 year to within 1 week.
- Designed a new spacer for lapping 3FOV primary mirrors which allows for more parts to fit on the machine at a time thus increasing lapping throughput by 300%.
- Developed new training program for training new employees at Generating workstation with more focus on the theory which reduced training time by 33%.
- Collaborate with quality assurance team by providing process expertise in investigation of nonconformances and development of corrective action plans.

Junior Manufacturing Engineer

March 2016 to February 2018

Royal Laser MFG Inc.

- Redesigned the sunglass display unit for an efficient manufacturing operation. This resulted in the reduction of parts by 55% while maintaining the same form and function.
- Designed new waste receptacle based on customer requirements which allowed the company to win a contract for 300 units.
- Designed heater panels and mounting bracket based on customer requirements which allowed the client to get CSA approval for the baseboard heater system.

Education

University of Toronto

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development Toronto, ON June 2022 to Current

Ydelay Inc.

Lean Six Sigma Greenbelt Toronto, ON November 2018 to November 2018

Ryerson University

Bachelor's in Mechanical Engineering Toronto, ON September 2011 to October 2015

Awards

e3 Improvement Award

September 2021

L3Harris Wescam Inc.

- Created an Excel VBA Macro to sort through the data of over 1000 test plates to identify obsolete test plates.
- The project was estimated to be a year long project, but the macro cut the time down to less than a week.
- The macro helped identify and remove over 55% of the obsolete test plates and free up shop floor space for a new equipment.